lkbennett.com 2018-09-28

# Privacy Policy | LKBennett-UK

This Privacy Policy was last reviewed and updated in May 2018 to take into account new data protection laws coming into force across the European Union, particularly the General Data Protection Regulation (also known as the GDPR). We are committed to protecting your privacy and we comply with the GDPR and the UK data protection rules (together with associated guidance) ("Data Protection Laws").

This Privacy Policy describes the information we may collect from you and explains how we use, store and share your personal data and supplements any fair processing notice provided to you.

This website ("the Website") is run by L.K.Bennett Limited (company no. 02699136 with registered office at Rivington House, 82 Great Eastern Street, London, EC2A 3JF) ("we" and "us").

**Please note** : this Privacy Policy does not cover links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices (including use of cookies) of other websites even if you accessed the third party website using links from our Website. We recommend that you check the policy of each website you visit and contact the owner or operator of such website if you have concerns or questions.

Any changes to this Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page, and where appropriate, notified to you by email. We will also post a notice on the Website landing page. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to this Privacy Policy.

## THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT & HOW WE USE IT

**POINT OF COLLECTION  
** | **INFORMATION COLLECTED  
** | **PURPOSE OF PROCESSING  
** | **WHO DO WE SHARE THE INFORMATION WITH  
**  
---|---|---|---  
Website  | Personal information, including but not limited to your name, postal address, email address, phone number, date of birth and any other information collected on registration or the ordering process through the Website | 

To fulfil the contract for goods and/or services between us and deal with orders, complaints and enquiries

| 

Delivery providers and couriers   
  
In-store | As above, for e-receipting  | 

(1) To send you an electronic version of your receipt as a service email (as part of our contractual relationship); and 

(2) To send you marketing communications where you have been given the opportunity by our staff to say no to this* | Third party service providers (specifically Y-receipts)  
Website/ in-store  | As above and through cookies (please see our [Cookie Policy](http://www.lkbennett.com/Cookies)) | To personalise and enrich your shopping experience on the Website, in marketing communications and in-store*  | 

Third party agencies appointed by us that collate and use this data to create a personalised service for you on our behalf

_Example:_ _M_ _ention Me,_ _Yieldify_  
  
Website | As above  | To ask you to complete surveys in respect of your products or customer experience* | Third party service providers   
Website | Browsing Information about you, including but not limited to your device (mobile, tablet, desktop, including location and your IP address. | 

Website, including what device you use most; to learn about your preferences and to help us manage your account. All in order so that we can improve our online experience so that you can have the best shopping experience, which is personalised to you. 

Please see our [cookies policy](http://www.lkbennett.com/cookies) for further information about what information may be automatically collected when you visit our Website. | Third party agencies (for example Google Adwords) appointed by us that collate and use this data to create a personalised service for you on our behalf and provide us with information about the users/ footfall to our Website  
Website, In-store, events, third party websites, social media | Personal information, including but not limited to your name, postal address, email address, phone number, date of birth and any other information collected on registration. Or through the ordering process on the Website or through you opting in to receive LK. Bennett marketing communications through other websites hosted by third parties | 

We want to keep you up to date with the latest offers and promotions as well as new collections/ collaborations. We ensure that we will only send you marketing communications if you want to receive marketing communications and have consented by opting-in either through our Website or via our in-store system.

_When we can send you marketing_

We can send you marketing communications if one of the following applies:

(1) You have negotiated a sale with us (i.e. sent us an enquiry or put something in your basket, but not completed the purchase); 

(2) You have bought something from us; 

(3) You have ticked an opt-in box or taken a similar positive action (for example ticking a box on registering an account) to say you want to hear from us.

In the case of (1) and (2) when we collect your details, we will give you the chance to opt-out of marketing communications

In each case you will be able to unsubscribe from marketing communications and we will give you this opportunity every time we send you a marketing communication. For example, if you wish to unsubscribe from our emails you can do so at any time, by clicking “unsubscribe” within our weekly newsletters/ emails

_Marketing by post_

We can also send you marketing communications through the post, where you haven't subscribed to the Mail Preference Service. We will continue to send you marketing communications by post, unless you object by contacting us by post, updating your preferences within the preference tab of your account or at 

_Update your preferences_

Where you are a registered customer, you can also update your preferences at any time by [logging into your account](https://www.lkbennett.com/login) and going into “Preferences” section

_Safeguards_

We also implement safeguards to ensure customers who have opted out of receiving such communications don't receive them*

| We will never share your personal information for marketing without your express consent  
At events (including, but not limited to store events) | Photographic images and other information (e.g. name, address and date of birth). | 

To the extent we use images of you (i.e. not within a group) for marketing or promotional materials, we will ask you to provide your consent and an image rights clearance, which you can always refuse

Where we take photographs of groups at these events, we are doing so for our legitimate business interest of using the images for marketing and promotional materials to promote our business. It is within your reasonable expectations that in attending a PR event, photographs will be taken and images used in this way* | Publication on the Website, L.K. Bennett social media site, marketing and promotional materials  
Customer call centre or "Live chat" through the website | 

Calls (which includes voice and personal information including order details), name, email address, phone number, IP address and "Live Chat" correspondence which may include order details  

| To fulfil the contract for goods and/or services between us and deal with orders, complaints and enquiries | The information is shared with our third party agency Ascensos (customer service team) and our "Live Chat" function is run through a 3rd party platform (Zendesk)  
 In-store  | CCTV images  | Your safety is a priority which is why we need to use CCTV images in-store to (a) protect you, our other customers and our staff from harm; and (b) to protect our business from theft. We consider it necessary and proportionate to process the information in this way and there is no alternative method in which we could guarantee the same outcomes. This will not negatively impact you or your shopping experience if you act lawfully within our stores* |    
 Email  | Personal information, including but not limited to your name, postal address, email address, phone number and CV/ application details. | To acknowledge and review job applications, carry out interviews and keep records and notes of interviews and other correspondence relating to your job application. 

We process this information because it is in our legitimate business interest to do so* and where you are successful to take steps to enter into an employment arrangement with you.

If your job application is successful, this information will be transferred to your personnel file and processed in line with our Employee Privacy Policy.  | Across our group  
Sole trader/ business contact info | Personal information, including but not limited to your name, postal address, email address, phone number and any other information collected during the business relationship. | As a sole trader, we will need to process your personal information in order to perform the contract we have with you  
If you are an individual representative of a business who has a relationship with us, it is in our legitimate interests to process your information in the course of that relationship and will be fully within your reasonable expectations | Across our group and with third parties, to the extent necessary to fulfil our contract/ business arrangement  
  |   |   |    
  
After you have registered your email address, you can also log into your account via the Website and amend your communication preferences and amend your personal preferences You can amend your preferences or opt out from marketing communications by using the  unsubscribe links within our electronic marketing communications, or updating your preferences within your account on the Website; sending an email to [customer.care@lkbennett.com](mailto:customer.care@lkbennett.com) or calling us on +44 (0)333 577 9900.

*Where we rely on "legitimate business interests" as the reason for processing your information, we have to carry out a balancing exercise to make sure your rights as an individual aren't impacted. In some cases, we have set out our balancing test above. Otherwise, as a result of our balancing test, which is detailed below, we have determined, acting reasonably and considering the circumstances, that we are able to process your personal data in accordance with the Data Protection Laws on the basis that we have a legitimate business interest.

We have a legitimate interest in processing your personal data as:

  * We need the information to respond to your enquiries 
  * We need the information to send you information; and
  * We would be unable to provide our services without processing your information.

We consider that it is reasonable for us to process your personal data for the purposes of our legitimate interests outlined above as (a) we process your personal data only so far as is necessary for such purpose and (b) it can be reasonably expected for us to process your personal data in this way.  In most cases the information is being processed for your benefit as well as ours.

## INFORMATION SECURITY

L.K.Bennett has put in place various security measures in accordance with up-to-date industry procedures as set out in this Privacy Policy to keep personal data as safe and secure as possible and to protect from unauthorised or unlawful processing and accidental loss, destruction or damage. However the Internet and email are not secure. Your communications may route through a number of countries before being delivered, may be intercepted by third parties and may not always reach the intended recipient – this is the nature of the World Wide Web/Internet. We cannot accept responsibility for any such unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.

We may transfer personal information to countries other than the country in which the data was originally collected in order to provide you with the services you have requested.  These countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information and may not provide the same level of protection

We have in place appropriate policies, rules and technical and organisational measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised or unlawful processing, and against accidental loss, destruction of or damage to personal information.  

You are responsible for protecting your password and username and must not share it with, or disclose it, to anyone.

## TO WHOM YOUR INFORMATION WILL BE DISCLOSED

Your information may, for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, be disclosed to the third parties set out in THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT above

We may disclose your personal information to any member of the L.K. Bennett Group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006 (" **L.K. Bennett Group** ").

We will only share your personal information with other members of the L.K. Bennett Group for marketing purposes where you have expressly opted-in/consented to the disclosure of your personal data for these purposes. 

We will only disclose your information to:

  * business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you
  * to our professional advisors (including without limitation tax, legal or other corporate advisors who provide professional services to the LK. Bennett Group);
  * to other third party suppliers for business administration or IT purposes
  * our affiliates and selected third parties, where you have expressly opted-out of receiving marketing from us / third parties, in which case we may share suppression lists with our affiliates and selected third parties, to ensure you do not receive unsolicited marketing.
  * analytics or search engines, including Google that enable us to optimise and improve your W ~~w~~ ebsite experience, as well as selected third parties
  * our regulators, law enforcement or fraud prevention agencies, as well as our legal advisers, courts, the Metropolitan police and any other authorised bodies, for the purposes of investigating any actual or suspected criminal activity or other regulatory or legal matters etc

We will disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * in the event that we consider selling or buying any business or assets, in which case we will disclose your personal data to any prospective sellers or buyers of such business or assets  

  * in the event of any insolvency situation (e.g. the administration or liquidation) of L.K. Bennett or any of its group entities
  * if we, or substantially all of our assets, are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by us about our customers will be one of the transferred assets
  * in order to enforce or apply our Website terms of use
  * to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our staff, our customers, or others.  This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations (including without limitation the local police or other local law enforcement agencies) for the purposes of staff and customer safety, crime prevention, fraud protection and credit risk reduction; and
  * if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation or regulatory requirements, or otherwise for the prevention or detection of fraud or crime.

## HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR DATA

We will typically keep your personal data for seven (7) years from (a) the closure of your account with us, or (b) your last purchase in order to enable us to deal with any issues or concerns you may have about how we handled your account/ order, and also to allow us to bring or defend legal proceedings.  In some circumstances, some of your data will be deleted in much shorter timescales, for example:

  * call recordings are kept for a maximum of 180 days from the date of recording
  * cookies are refreshed in accordance with our [cookies policy](http://www.lkbennett.com/cookies) 
  * unsuccessful job applications/CVs will be kept for 6 months
  * CCTV recordings are kept for a maximum of 30 days from the date of recording and are only kept longer where the footage relates to an identified incident and is required for legal reasons
  * Marketing consents are refreshed after a period of 3 years

## YOUR RIGHTS

You have a number of rights under Data Protection Laws in relation to the way we process your personal data.  These are set out **below**.  You may contact us using the details on our Website (or by contacting [customer.care@lkbennett.com](mailto:customer.care@lkbennett.com) or calling us on +44 (0)333 577 9900) to exercise any of these rights, and we will respond to any request received from you promptly and in compliance with Data Protection Laws.  

**NUMBER** | **DESCRIPTION OF RIGHT**  
---|---  
RIGHT 1 | A right to access personal data held by us about you  
RIGHT 2 | A right to require us to rectify any inaccurate personal data held by us about you  
RIGHT 3 | A right to require us to erase personal data held by us about you.  This right will only apply where (for example): we no longer need to use the personal data to achieve the purpose we collected it for; or where you withdraw your consent if we are using your personal data based on your consent; or where you object to the way we process your data (in line with Right 6 below).   
RIGHT 4 | In certain circumstances, a right to restrict our processing of personal data held by us about you.  This right will only apply where (for example): you dispute the accuracy of the personal data held by us; or where you would have the right to require us to erase the personal data but would prefer that our processing is restricted instead; or where we no longer need to use the personal data to achieve the purpose we collected it for, but you require the data for the purposes of dealing with legal claims  
RIGHT 5 | In certain circumstances, a right to receive personal data, which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format.  You also have the right to require us to transfer this personal data to another organisation, at your request  
RIGHT 6 | A right to object to our processing of personal data held by us about you where the processing of such data is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests, unless we are able to demonstrate, on balance, legitimate grounds for continuing to process personal data which override your rights or which are for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims  
RIGHT 7 | A right for you not to be subject to a decision based solely on an automated process, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you  
RIGHT 8 | A right to withdraw your consent, where we are relying on it to use your personal data (for example, to provide you with marketing information about our services or products).   
  
We encourage you to contact us first if you have any queries, comments or concerns about the way we handle your data. However, if you are not satisfied with our handling of any request by you in relation to your rights or concerns, you also have the right to make a complaint to our lead supervisory authority, which is the UK's Information Commissioner's Office.  Their address is: First Contact Team, Information Commissioner's Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, SK9 5AF

## FURTHER INFORMATION

For further information from us on data protection and privacy or any requests concerning your personal information please write to L.K.Bennett, Rivington House, 82 Great Eastern, London, EC2A 3JF or email us on [customer.care@lkbennett.com](mailto:customer.care@lkbennett.com).
